<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Operating System &#8211; The New Vibes</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/operating-system/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 04:19:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Update and Agree Or Lose Your Whatsapp &#8211; Whatsapp&#8217;s New Terms</title>
		<link>/2021/01/07/update-and-agree-or-lose-your-whatsapp-whatsapp-new-terms/</link>
					<comments>/2021/01/07/update-and-agree-or-lose-your-whatsapp-whatsapp-new-terms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joseph Anim Darko]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 04:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Operating System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whatsapp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://buildupmultimedia.com/?p=1742</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Unfortunately, it has been noted that WhatsApp running on older Android and iPhone devices will cease to be supported on the latest version of the messaging app, requiring owners to either update their mobile operating system or buy a new compatible mobile device...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center"></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/whatsapp-update-1-1-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4206"/></figure></div>


<p></p>



<p>Unfortunately, it has been noted that older Android and iPhone devices will cease to support the latest version of the messaging app, requiring owners to either update their mobile operating system or buy a new compatible mobile device. More importantly, any device not running at least Ice Cream Sandwich &#8211; Android 4.0.3 or, iPhone not running iOS 9 or newer, will no longer be able to open or operate the Facebook-owned app &#8211; <strong>Whatsapp</strong>.</p>



<p>Android phones or devices that will lose WhatsApp support include the LG Optimus Black, Samsung Galaxy S2 and HTC Desire. This also applies to some of the iphone model devices between iPhone 4S and iOS 9; those that we&#8217;re release before iOS 9 but not before iphone 4S.</p>



<p>This, this implies that all iPhone models up to the iPhone 4 model will not be able to support the popular messaging app &#8211; WhatsApp, as these phones are not capable of updating to iOS 9 and rendered incompatible. However, owners of iphone 4S to iOS 9 can still update to a compatible operating system if they are yet to do so.</p>



<p>Phone owners will either see an updated Terms and Conditions when opening their WhatsApp messenger with the choice to agree or not, or can see the software update version their device is using by checking the settings section of the device. As for iPhone users, it can be found right under:</p>



<p> <strong>Settings </strong>> <strong>General </strong>>  <strong>Software update</strong>.<br></p>



<p><strong>Below are the Phone models will lose WhatsApp support from 1 January, 2021:</strong></p>



<p>1. HTC Desire</p>



<p>2. Apple iPhone 1-4</p>



<p>3. Motorola Droid Razr</p>



<p>4. Samsung Galaxy S2</p>



<p>5. LG Optimus Black</p>



<p>6. Any Android released before 2010</p>



<p><strong>List Of Phones that will need to update to at least iOS9 or Android OS 4.0.3:</strong></p>



<p><strong>iPhone Models</strong>;</p>



<ul>
<li>IPhone 4S</li>



<li>IPhone 5</li>



<li>iPhone 5S</li>



<li>iPhone 6</li>



<li>iPhone 6S<br></li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Android Models;</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>HTC Thunderbolt</li>



<li>Motorola Droid 4</li>



<li>Samsung Galaxy Note</li>



<li>HTC Sensation</li>



<li>Samsung Galaxy S3 or newer version</li>



<li>LG Lucid</li>



<li>Sony Experia Pro or newer<br></li>
</ul>



<p><br>The popular messaging app terms and conditions are already in force, whereby all users must either agree in order to keep using the app or lose access to their messages as well as the app itself.</p>



<p><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/01/07/update-and-agree-or-lose-your-whatsapp-whatsapp-new-terms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
