<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Whatsapp &#8211; The New Vibes</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/whatsapp/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 12:24:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Update and Agree Or Lose Your Whatsapp &#8211; Whatsapp&#8217;s New Terms</title>
		<link>/2021/01/07/update-and-agree-or-lose-your-whatsapp-whatsapp-new-terms/</link>
					<comments>/2021/01/07/update-and-agree-or-lose-your-whatsapp-whatsapp-new-terms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joseph Anim Darko]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 04:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Operating System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whatsapp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://buildupmultimedia.com/?p=1742</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Unfortunately, it has been noted that WhatsApp running on older Android and iPhone devices will cease to be supported on the latest version of the messaging app, requiring owners to either update their mobile operating system or buy a new compatible mobile device...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center"></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/whatsapp-update-1-1-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4206"/></figure></div>


<p></p>



<p>Unfortunately, it has been noted that older Android and iPhone devices will cease to support the latest version of the messaging app, requiring owners to either update their mobile operating system or buy a new compatible mobile device. More importantly, any device not running at least Ice Cream Sandwich &#8211; Android 4.0.3 or, iPhone not running iOS 9 or newer, will no longer be able to open or operate the Facebook-owned app &#8211; <strong>Whatsapp</strong>.</p>



<p>Android phones or devices that will lose WhatsApp support include the LG Optimus Black, Samsung Galaxy S2 and HTC Desire. This also applies to some of the iphone model devices between iPhone 4S and iOS 9; those that we&#8217;re release before iOS 9 but not before iphone 4S.</p>



<p>This, this implies that all iPhone models up to the iPhone 4 model will not be able to support the popular messaging app &#8211; WhatsApp, as these phones are not capable of updating to iOS 9 and rendered incompatible. However, owners of iphone 4S to iOS 9 can still update to a compatible operating system if they are yet to do so.</p>



<p>Phone owners will either see an updated Terms and Conditions when opening their WhatsApp messenger with the choice to agree or not, or can see the software update version their device is using by checking the settings section of the device. As for iPhone users, it can be found right under:</p>



<p> <strong>Settings </strong>> <strong>General </strong>>  <strong>Software update</strong>.<br></p>



<p><strong>Below are the Phone models will lose WhatsApp support from 1 January, 2021:</strong></p>



<p>1. HTC Desire</p>



<p>2. Apple iPhone 1-4</p>



<p>3. Motorola Droid Razr</p>



<p>4. Samsung Galaxy S2</p>



<p>5. LG Optimus Black</p>



<p>6. Any Android released before 2010</p>



<p><strong>List Of Phones that will need to update to at least iOS9 or Android OS 4.0.3:</strong></p>



<p><strong>iPhone Models</strong>;</p>



<ul>
<li>IPhone 4S</li>



<li>IPhone 5</li>



<li>iPhone 5S</li>



<li>iPhone 6</li>



<li>iPhone 6S<br></li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Android Models;</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>HTC Thunderbolt</li>



<li>Motorola Droid 4</li>



<li>Samsung Galaxy Note</li>



<li>HTC Sensation</li>



<li>Samsung Galaxy S3 or newer version</li>



<li>LG Lucid</li>



<li>Sony Experia Pro or newer<br></li>
</ul>



<p><br>The popular messaging app terms and conditions are already in force, whereby all users must either agree in order to keep using the app or lose access to their messages as well as the app itself.</p>



<p><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/01/07/update-and-agree-or-lose-your-whatsapp-whatsapp-new-terms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Whatsapp New Feature &#8211; You Can Now Be Able To Permanently Mute Messages</title>
		<link>/2021/01/01/whatsapp-new-feature-you-will-soon-be-able-to-permanently-mute-messages/</link>
					<comments>/2021/01/01/whatsapp-new-feature-you-will-soon-be-able-to-permanently-mute-messages/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joseph Anim Darko]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 09:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barrier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boundaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Build Up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whatsapp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://consultbuildup.blogspot.com/2020/10/whatsapp-new-feature-you-will-soon-be.html</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This feature initially permits users to disallow message notifications from groups and individual contacts for a period of time specifically to suit the user, now allows it without any time limit even for groups... ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div></div>
<div><b>&nbsp;</b></div>
<div><b>&nbsp;</b></div>
<div>
<div class="separator" style="clear:both;text-align:center;"><a style="margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;" href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/0156f-img_20201009_041730-1-1-1.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="https://repentedanalyst.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/01633-img_20201009_041730.jpg" width="640" height="600" border="0"></a></div>
<div class="separator" style="clear:both;text-align:center;"></div>
<p>WhatsApp, The online prominent instant messaging platform, has now made available an updated feature &#8211; The mute feature, for all Android users which has been used by a lot of Android users worldwide since its release. This feature initially permits users to disallow message notifications from groups and individual contacts for a period of time specifically to suit the user, now allows it without any time limit.</p>
<p>This means users will not have to periodically revisit their mute decision to update it all the time. Until then, users could only mute notifications for 8 hours, 1 week, or a year in their WhatsApp settings, however, the recently launched option is now ‘Always’ and it is intended to replace the ‘1 year’ option.</p>
</div>
<div></div>
<div class="separator" style="clear:both;text-align:center;"><a style="margin-left:1em;margin-right:1em;" href="/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/b48d0-img_20201009_034512-1-1-1.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="https://repentedanalyst.files.wordpress.com/2020/12/bc6dd-img_20201009_034512.jpg" width="562" height="640" border="0"></a></div>
<div>The ‘mute notification’ choice can be activated by tapping on the three dots at the top right corner in a chat window which then will allow you to select a duration of your choice. WhatsApp does not notify affected contact or group of this decision when initiated. You should note that muting a group or private chat will not necessarily stop their messages from trooping in, it will only stop notifying you about the messages from the groups or people you have muted.</p>
<p>Aside the general mute feature relating to messages, WhatsApp also enables users to mute their status updates. Muted statuses are usually hidden just below the list of permitted ones, but can be viewed at the user’s will. This mute option is one of WhatsApp&#8217;s own way of helping users to create barriers or boundaries on whom ever they decide to interact with or not on the platform and also to avoid unnecessary spams and annoying notifications from these people or groups.</p>
<p>However, the good thing about this is, it is only a modest restraint because the messages from muted contacts can still be found on the list of unread messages. Although a severe measure or action is the ‘block’ feature which is available on most social media platforms to prevent privacy invasion and spams. This avoids any form of dealings with contacts considered as threats but unfortunately, it cannot be used on WhatsApp groups. To compensate for that, the most helpful and effective way of preventing unwanted messages from those groups is to entirely exit the groups, which has been a lot of help to most people regarding invasion.</p>
<p>Apart from this, users can change their privacy settings to allow only known or specific contacts to add them to groups they prefer. As at now, both the mute and block actions can be reversed if the need be. For now, the ‘Always’ mute option has been added to the list of terrific features on the prominent messaging app &#8211; Whatsapp.</p>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>Meanwhile, aside the &#8216;mute forever&#8217; feature already existing in Telegram, there is another feature which enables messages or accounts to self-destruct after a period of long idle period of time may also be accommodated on WhatsApp platform in the future.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/01/01/whatsapp-new-feature-you-will-soon-be-able-to-permanently-mute-messages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
